Alright, by friends, let's take the discussion forward with inheritance, we will have a look
at overriding and exceptions in our number one regarding scope. Now let's take the idea forward
and if you zoom in to class human, see we have big eat and walk with their bodies, right?
And Ranjith has a choice to override eat and walk and breathe or not, doesn't take the choice,
show that it takes the choice to eat and walk but doesn't take the choice to breathe, that's perfectly
fine but now if you zoom in to class human, what sense does it make to have the logic of
how humans eat and walk in human because think about this human as just speak an idea,
as just you have just drawn out the idea of how humans would act in the real world on a piece of
paper because think about the super classes as just being blue, blueprints and abstract ideas
or even or even something that is not concrete by itself, right? What does it telling me, right?
So, because Ranjith walks and eats in the same way every human does, obviously has a choice
but doesn't take the choice, right? But that's not how things work in the real world because in
the real world what you would see is every human would have its own way of eating, have their
own ways of walking, breathing and crying and running and smiling, right? That's make them
unique humans unique individuals, something unique to them and that is why I zoom into this
and introduce you to the concept of abstract classes. Remember we are discussed abstracting before,
this is how we implement that in Java, the first way to do that is to abstract classes and it's
such a great idea, right? Now, what are abstract classes? They're defined or declared with the keyword
abstract and that's the first thing about them, the second thing is an abstract class in Java
can have zero to n number of abstract methods, right? What are abstract methods,
methods which are defined without a body and with the keyword abstract? That is, what I do is
I leave breathe like this concrete, I'll call it a concrete method now and I make eat and walk as
abstract, see, study colon, study colon, let me remove this final, you already know what do they do
and I'll declare them with the keyword abstract. So now we have three methods in this class,
breathe is concrete with a body that's fine because we still want humans to know how do we breathe,
otherwise a new baby bonds up is born in the world and immediately dies because they don't even
know how to breathe but they learn other traits like eat walking and running and crying after
some time, right, but at least they do have to breathe, at least they're able to make it through
and until they learn other traits. That's the great idea we're talking about
the Almighty's idea of human, right? And that's why what I said is essentially,
I said humans should have breathe eat and walk but Almighty will not tell us how to eat and how to
walk, we have to make that up on our own, we have to understand that our own way of these two
on our techniques such a great idea, right? And what happens is immediately in error because
the abstract methods now often abstract class need to be overridden in the subclass or the subclass
also needs to be defined as abstract. That's why we're getting an error here. Why? Because
see, now we're getting three methods down inside our genes. One is concrete, that's not a problem,
plantate has a choice to override that or not, but plantate does not have a choice to override
eat and walk because they have come as abstract and abstract class, abstract methods can only
be inside abstract classes, they cannot be normal classes, so either we'll declare this as abstract,
error goes away, but if you want to have a mutation, what you would do, you will have a body of it.
And still in error, unless you have a body of walk as it is. See, the error goes away,
because I did not override read because read wasn't necessarily meant to be overridden. That's
my choice. That's RNG choice. You want to do it or not because it's concrete, but that abstract
methods of again, I repeat it for you to rule, and subtract methods of an abstract class need to
be implemented in the subclass or the subclass also needs to be declared as abstract. And you're
seeing this small i and i that means see whether error upwards, they are being seen, it takes
due to the declaration, and this one takes you to the implementation. See, say RNG, yes.
So the same goes with Schweta, the same goes with Sneha, but for now, let's come into Sneha,
because it was extending in a final class, and you know final classes now cannot be overridden,
sorry, cannot be extended inherited in Java, right. So, same choices with Schweta, right,
but guess what now, and I'll just put in a sound here later on, you'll put the logic for how
RNG walks and eats here, but I'll just when I'll say RNG on eat in ways only. Make sense? Let me
comment this, paste it here, RNG can walk his own way, right, and then Schweta obviously had
her own way of eating and walking, she still has a choice of breathing and she does that, and same
D, let's remove this annotation, I'll get back to that in some time, and just put up written
here as well, that is Schweta, own way of it, right, that's a test still choice, otherwise you're not
going to error, but abstract methods, they need to be overridden, and why is this a such a great idea,
because it promotes inheritance, why? Because now RNG has to have a deep nose, I would be able to
eat and walk, but how I would have to figure that on my own, Schweta knows I have a version of
eat and walk, but I would have to figure how do I walk and eat in my own way, but I still have a
version of breathe, whether I want to stick to the generic way or have my own way, that's
completely on my own, right, that's the great power of inheritance with abstract, abstract glasses, not.
The third rule about abstract glasses is, abstract glasses in Java cannot be instantiated,
that's we cannot create objects of them, now it makes sense why, because that's it,
you were able to create an object of human, what would you do with it? You can't call human or to
eat and walk, because these are just declarations, but you might have a count grant given,
what wrong did breathe do, can't we call new human or breathe? Yes, we call it, but think about it
in the literary sense, and that is, breathe in human, eat and human and walk in human, where
never meant to be of humans, this was just as the ideal class, the ideal type that all subclasses
looked up to for behavior, so the super class here, abstract class, it just defines the behavior
for all the subclasses to implement themselves, right, it will not tell them how now, it would
just tell them what do you need, but how, just figure it out on your own, that's why it's such a
great idea, and that's why we cannot create objects of super class, that's abstract glasses in Java,
and now, let's come in this, and you can call rangit.eat, walk and breathe,
shredder.eat, walk and breathe, just have a look at this, what will we get once green, see,
humans breathe with rangit or breathe, because still rangit had a choice,
breathe was a concrete method, he took that choice, that is indeed not all right, that's right,
but rangit was made to eat and walk in his own way, particular way, so now we know how rangit
walks and dates, shredder took the choice of breathing as well, and shredder has their own way of
eating, has their own way of walking, and still can't dance because it's our own method, right,
so that is how we can do stuff with, with abstract glasses, and now, if you try to do
new human, immediately in error, it says plain and simple, that is, human is abstract cannot be
instantiated, I'll say, doesn't work now, why human is abstract, right, it would not work now,
right, so again, I'll just repeat the rules for you, before ending this video wrapping this up,
that is the first rule is, abstract glasses are there to promote inheritance, because by it said,
what would you do with them, you cannot create an object, you cannot call the methods, right,
almost useless, doesn't make sense, it's just therefore one reason to promote
and courage inheritance, abstract glasses are defined with a keyword abstract, they can have
from zero to end of our website methods, abstract methods can only be inside abstract glasses,
they are declared with a keyword abstract without bodies, ending with semicolon,
and abstract methods of an abstract class need to be implemented in the subclass, or the subclass,
also needs to be declared as abstract, abstract glasses in Java cannot be instantiated,
we cannot create objects out of them, in the next video, we'll take this even a step further
with another concept that you will just, you're just going to learn,